Guide to the Utility Workers Union of America, Local 1-2 Records WAG.131
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Bargaining Records, 1935-2002, undated; 3.4 Linear Feet in 3 and a half record cartons, 2 oversize folders, 1 D-2 cassette, 1 VHS cassette, and 3 buttons
  - Subseries V.A: 1997 accession, 1958-1993; 1.3 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 10 folders
    - Arbitrations, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Arbitrations, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Arbitrations, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Arbitrations, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subseries V.B: Contracts, 1935-2002, undated; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 13 folders, 1 oversize folder, 1 VHS cassette, and 2 buttons
    This subseries is arranged chronologically by year.
    This subseries contains drafts and printed agreements between Local 1-2 and ConEd; the Employees Representation Plans of Bronx Gas and Electric Company and Consolidated Edison Employees and the Consolidated Edison Company of New York; the Brotherhood of Consolidated Edison Employees and Consolidated Edison Company of New York; Joint Council of Locals 1, 2, 3, 4, and 7 and Consolidated Edison System Companies; and other locals and ConEd. Also included is a 1978 agreement between the Jamaica Water Supply Company and Local 1-2. The negotiations are documented through correspondence and memoranda between the locals, the companies, and the National Labor Relations Board regarding the creation of and deliberation around contracts and minutes of their negotiation meetings. Other items include payroll classifications and job titles booklets; lists of employees denied wage progression increases; issues of Bargaining Bulletin, The Record, and Utility Workers' Light; handbooks on mobilizing members; surveys of union members regarding where they work and what issues in the contract are important to them; notices to members regarding the contract process; newspaper clippings regarding contract negotiations; and buttons supporting ratification of different contracts. There are approximately 50 photographs of a rally held in Union Square, Manhattan in support of the 1992 contract.
    - Contracts, 1935-1953 (Box 4, Folder 17-27)
    - Contracts, 1954-2000 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 3, 5, Box 5, Folder 1-19, Box 9, Cassette 2, Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Contracts, 2000-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Contracts--Buttons, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Subseries V.C: Grievances, 1969-1975; 0.1 Linear Feet in 3 folders
    This subseries contains correspondence, memoranda, and reports regarding grievance trials and appeals of two members of Local 1-2 and is arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Mazzola, Frank T., 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
    - Weidman, Frank J., 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Subseries V.D: Mergers, 1945-2002; 0.1 Linear Feet in 4 file folders and 1 oversize folder
    This subseries is arranged in numerical order by name of local.
    This subseries contains correspondence, constitutions, and agreements of mergers between Local 1-2 and Local 4; Local 1-2 and Local 8; and Local 1-2 and Local 381.
    - Local 4, 1945-1949, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Local 8, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7-8, Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 3)
    - Local 381, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Subseries V.E: Strikes, 1989-2002; 0.4 Linear Feet in 12 folders, 1 D-2 cassette, and 1 button
    This subseries contains material from all stages of the strikes, from proposal to planning to strike to resolution. Most of the strikes were in response to failed contract negotiations between Local 1-2 and ConEd, but some of the material documents Local 1-2 striking in solidarity with other unions, including the Communications Workers of America in 1989 and the Utility Workers Union of America, Locals 375 and 381 in 1998. This material includes Local 1-2 Bargaining Bulletins, notices, and posters communicating the position of the Local. Material regarding the planning of strikes includes picket duty lists, schedules, and other planning documents, as well as correspondence between officials from the Local and the National, ConEd officials, and politicians. Other materials include newspaper clippings and VHS cassettes with news reports on the strikes; photographs of demonstrations and rallies; and buttons documenting political parties and positions in regards to the strikes. There are three photographs from a strike in the 1990s which could not be positively dated and are filed at the end of the material.
    Materials added to the collection in 2017 include additional photos, flyers, and a scrapbook related to the 1998 Local 381 Strike. They also contain videos of press coverage of demonstrations demonstration against Con-Edison and in support of the Indian Point Utility Workers Union (UAUW, Local 1-2), and a small assortment of bargaining agreements and bylaws.
    - 1989 Strike, 1986-1990 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - 1992 Strike, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Cassette 1, Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - 1996 Strike (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
    - 1998 Strike, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 17-18, Box 11, Folder 3-4, Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 5)
    - 1998 Strike--Buttons (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 1998 Strike--Photograph (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS007, Folder 1)
    - 1998 Strike--Scrapbook (Box 12)
    - 2000-2002 Strikes (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - Photographs, 1990s (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Series VI: General Files, 1927, 1941-2006; 1.9 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 1 oversize folder, 3 VHS cassettes, 3 CDs, 2 audio cassettes, 1 audio reel, and 10 buttons
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, with material from the 1997 accession filed separately from the 2003 accretion.
  This series contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, newsletters, photographs, programs, and VHS cassettes regarding a number of topics, including different political parties within the Local, including Administration, New Directions Caucus, Members 1st Party, and the Justice Party; the trusteeship instituted by the National in 1998 due to alleged mismanagement of funds by the president of the Local, Joseph Flaherty; histories of the Local, ConEd, and other organizations; the 50th anniversary of the local; social events held by the Local; efforts by the Progressive Labor Party to influence Local members; Local financial records; legislative files; the Local's dealings with individual employers other than ConEd (small numbers of Local members were employed by private companies); and the 1940s detail organizing efforts within ConEd which resulted in the replacement of older company unions by the Brotherhood of Consolidated Edison Employees.
  - Administration Party sticker, circa 1980s (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Around the System, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Asplundh Tree Expert Company, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Black Solidarity Alliance, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brotherhood of Consolidated Edison Employees: Newsletters; Local 3 and Local 5, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Buttons, 1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Campaign against Con Edison, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Clancy, John, 1965, 1973, 1987, 1990, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Coalition Committee (Local 369, Boston), 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Coalition for Union Democracy: Rank-and-File Newsletter, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Con Ed Contract Campaign, 1996 December 13 (Box 14, Cassette 7)
  - Con Ed Employees Mutual Aid Society, 1948, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Con Ed Environmental Policy, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Con Ed Investigation" Eyewitness News ABC TV, 2006 May 9 (Box 14, Cassette 5-6)
  - Con Ed Organizing, 1941, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Con Edison pension and retirement plans, 1944, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - ConEdison Special Report: Selected TV News Reports from World Trade Center Coverage, 2001 September (Box 13, Cassette 19)
  - Con Edison special telephone directories, 1980, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Con Edison's Drug Awareness Program pamphlet, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (C.I.O.) affiliation, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Consolidated Edison System Companies Data Book 1930-1951, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Convention (UWUA), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cuban Workers Party of Con Ed, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Deregulation, 1996-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dickey-Lincoln Bill, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - East River Station newsletter, 1964 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 4)
  - Employee committees policy, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - The Energizer: New Directions Caucus Newsletter, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Local Union Reports EEO-3, 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Expenditures, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Expenditures, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Facts on the origins of Local 1-2 presented by M. Sampson, 1964 (Box 9, Cassette 12)
  - Federation of Utility Employees, 1942-1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Federation Party newsletter, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary of Local 1-2, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 37, Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 4)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary: Souvenir Program, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Financial Statements, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Financial Statements, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Financial Statements, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Financial Statements, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - George Meany: The Making of a Freedom Fighter, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - History of Local 1-2: Interview with James Beamish, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Indian Point nuclear power plant, 1976, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Job Bulletins, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Job evaluation manuals, 1979-1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 4-7)
  - Kerry, John and UAUW "Building a Stronger America", 2004 August 20 (Box 14, Cassette 8)
  - Labor Clips #3 NLRB Demonstration, 1993 May 27 (Box 13, Cassette 9-10)
  - Legal Fees, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Legislative and Cope Committee, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Local 1-2 Banner, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Local 1-2 Bulletin, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Local 1-2 bumper sticker, Undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 4)
  - Local 1-2 charter, 1945 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 2)
  - Local 1-2 News Bulletin, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Local 1-2 and the Salvation Army advertisement, 1986 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 2)
  - Local 1-2 Utility Workers, 1995 (Box 13, Cassette 11)
  - Mc Mahon, J.: Irish Materials, 1949-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Manual Underground Cable System, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Members 1st Party notices and fliers, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - National Press Club John Sweeney, 2001 February 5 (Box 13, Cassette 12)
  - Newsletter of the Unity Party: The Fightback Challenger, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Notices, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Officers and executive board lists, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, 1948, 1964, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: General, 1980-2001 (Box 7, Folder 16-18)
  - Photographs: Philip Varrichio, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Photographs: Willie Ryan retirement party, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Power Line: UWUA Local 1-2 Shop Stewards Bulletin, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1963, 1971, 1975, 1983, 1990, 1994-1997 (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Progressive Labor Party, 1970, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Rate Hearings, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - The Record, 1987, 1994, 1997-2004 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 4, Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Regional Conference, 1966 December 9-December 10 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Report on Health Impact on Low Level Radiation, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Retirement Plan, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Safety Grants, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Security Party Highlights, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - S.G. Blakly Tree Company, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Sixty-Fifth Anniversary: Souvenir Program, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Some Lessons Learned: Recollections of 15 Years as Chairman of Consolidated Edison 1967-1982, by Charles F. Luce, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Stand Up to Con Edison, 1992 June 15 (Box 13, Cassette 13)
  - The Story of Electricity, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Tree Preservation Company, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Trusteeship, 1997-2003 (Box 7, Folder 27-29, Box 9, Cassette 4)
  - Truth-in-Lending, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Utility Workers Union Health and Safety Manual, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Utility Workers Union of America membership totals, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - UWUA A.F.L.-C.I.O. "Indian Point Utility Workers Rally" New York Coverage, 2002 February 7 (Box 14, Cassette 14-16)
  - UWUA A.F.L.-C.I.O. Local 1-2 Utility Workers Spring 1995 (Box 9, Cassette 5)
  - UWUA "Deregulation Bill", 2000 October 8 (Box 13, Cassette 17)
  - UWUA Region 1, 1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Waters, Gerald (Jerry), 1998, 2002, undated (Box 7, Folder 32, Box 9, Cassette 3)
  - Waters, Gerald (Jerry): Cornell University New York State School of Indutrial and Labor Relations, 1991, 1996-1997, 2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 33-38)
  - Waterside Station 1901-2001: One Hundred Years of Power at Waterside (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "Workers Exposed at Indian Point Unit 3" Eyewitness News ABC TV, 2000 March 13 (Box 14, Cassette 18)
  - World Assembly of Youth, 1964 July 28 (Box 9, Reel 1, Box 10, Cd 1-3, Cassette 6-7)
- Series VII: Archived Websites, February 2009-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  The website of Local 1-2 of the Utility Workers Union of America includes information on their political action committee, their publication, The Record dating back to 2006, images and other audiovisual materials, news listings, and event listings. Capture of the website began in 2009 and focused on the Employee Free Choice Act; World Trade Center injuries litigation; union elections and results; contract negotiations with Trans Canada, Con Edison, Entergy, NRG Energy, Reliant Energy, and the New York Power Authority; business agent contact information; and other documents related to benefits, grievances, and by-laws. In 2012, the website redesigned to include a photo gallery; member submitted news; videos; Hurricane Sandy response; Trans-Pacific Partnership; and political action campaigns. In 2015, the website redesigned again and focused on by-law revisions; injured workers protectings; support of nuclear facility closures; labor day parade; the young workers program; Rosary Hill fundraising; hurricane relief; heat waves; death announcements; and other membership meeting announcements. In 2020, the website began to focus on the union's response to the COVID-19 pandemic and contract negotiations with Con Edison. Up until the most recent web design in 2021, most news was posted as a pdf attachement in the website. In 2021, the highlighted the SUEZ contract negotiations; renewable energy union wariness; and COVID-19 vaccine requirements. The crawl also includes captures of the union's YouTube channel.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  http://uwua1-2.org/ is captured monthly. https://www.youtube.com/user/uwualocal12/videos/ is captured semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of uwua1-2.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Website was rescoped to attempt to capture the YouTube videos embedded in the website.
  In 2023, YouTube URLs were changed to better capture the videos on the channel.
- Series VIII: Conferences and Conventions Files, 1948-2003; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 oversize folder, 6 1/4" audio reels, 9 audio cassettes, and 16 CDs
  This series is arranged alphabetically by convention title and chronologically within that arrangement.
  This series contains correspondence and notices regarding election of delegates to UWUA National Conventions; agenda and minutes of conference sessions at the UWUA Nuclear Conference; and audio recordings of Educational and Regional Conferences held in 1964.
  UWUA Constitutional Conventions are documented through proceedings, officers reports, and photographs. The proceedings include transcripts of remarks and reports given at sessions. The officers reports outline important issues facing officers between conventions, including contract negotiations, financial operations of the National Union, and educational, political, and health initiatives. The photographs document panels, attendees, speakers, and social events at the conventions.
  - New York State AFL-CIO 27th Constitutional Convention: Photographs, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Region 1 Conference: Photographs, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Utility Workers Union of America Constitutional Conventions, 1947-1948, 1983-1999, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 3-10, Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Utility Workers Union of America National Convention, 1996-1998 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS003, Folder 3, Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Utility Workers Union of America Nuclear Conference, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Educational Conference, Friday, 1964 April 3 (Box 9, Cassette 10-11, Box 10, Reel 6, Cd 17-19)
  - Educational Conference, Friday Afternoon, 1964 April 3 (Box 10, Reel 4, Box 9, Cassette 7, Cd 11-12)
  - Educational Conference, Saturday A.M., 1964 April 4 (Box 10, Cd 13-16, Box 9, Cassette 8-9, Reel 5)
  - Regional Conference, Saturday P.M., 1964 May 23 (Box 10, Reel 1, Box 9, Cassette 3, Cd 4-5)
  - Regional Conference, Friday, 1964 May 22 (Box 10, Reel 2, Box 9, Cassette 4, Cd 6-7)
  - Regional Conference, Friday A.M., 1964 May 22 (Box 10, Cd 8-10, Reel 3, Box 9, Cassette 5-6)